Hello.
So in this second presentation we will be talking about the type A communication.
So I will be presenting the different exchange between a reader and the card, or between a PCD and
a pack during a type A communication.
I will present the different commands sent by the reader and the different answers sent by the card.
Also, I will present the characteristics and the details that we conclude from any comment or any answer.
So the first command that the reader will send it will be the request a command rec a command which
will be presented by the byte 26.
So the request a command is the first command to be sent during the communication.
The request a command is sent by the reader to generate the field for the card that supports the type
A.
In fact, basically, the reader can send a polling request A or request B, and then the card will
be answered.
So if it's a type A card, it will answer to the request a command.
Also, the request A is sent within a short frame.
Then the card will answer to the request A by a response called a TCA answer to request A, which consists
of two bytes zero four and zero zero.
So the TCA is the first answer to be sent by the card.
In fact, all the cards in the Idar State will respond with a TCA to the request a command from the
TCA response.
We can get the UID size if it's single, double or triple.
Once done, the reader then will send the anti-collision command, for example 93 and 20.
This command is used in the Anti-collision loop.
It's composed of two bytes SEL and KNVB.
It's transmitted in a bit oriented anti-collision frame.
The purpose is to get the UID from one card if we have many in the field.
So the phenomenon of anti-collision is the phenomenon where the reader will select one card from a group
of card that they are into the field.
For example, when you go to a restaurant with your friends and all all of you will put at the same
time the cards into the field of the reader.
The reader will select randomly one of the cards to communicate with, so only one of the cards will
pay the reader.
So after that, the card will answer with an anti-collision response.
For example, zero eight, zero one, zero two, 46, and 40.
This answer is used in the Anti-collision loop to the Anti-collision command.
Then the reader will send the select command in order to select the card.
So this command is sent in order to select a card to continue the communication with.
After that, the card will answer with this sack.
Select acknowledgment, for example 20 FC and 70.
In fact, this is the response that we get when we finally select the card.
It.
So the select and SRK, the purpose of this is to select officially the card that we will continue the
communication with the SRK shows if the card also supports the ISO 14,440 3-4 or not.
So we chose if the card supports supports the layer four of the ISO 14 443 standard, then the reader
will send the air ATS command the request for answer to select command.
In fact, this is the command that the PCD sends after receiving the SRK, the select acknowledgment
and it consists of four bytes E0 80, 31 and 73.
For example.
Once done, the card will answer with the ATS answer to select.
So this is the response for the air ATS.
Through this response, we may know the following information.
If different bit rates for each direction is supported or not.
Also, the values of the bit rate supported in each direction.
In fact, ATS for me is the most important answer during a type A communication.
In fact, it gives us the information about the speed that the card supports and that they can use to
for the communication between the reader and the card during the exchange of information.
In fact, basically the communication from the first request a to the response, it's it's done in 106
kilobit per second.
The all the time we change the bit rate when we go to the exchange of information, when we start exchanging
the I blocks, and this information about the maximum bit rate that the card can support, we can get
a.
From the ashes.
Once done, the reader will send the command protocol and parameter selection.
In fact, this is the command through which we choose the bit rate that we will continue the communication
with.
So through the ATS, the reader will know which values of the speed or which values of the bit rates
the card can support, and then through the PS or through the protocol and parameter selection, the
reader and the card will agree on a bit rate to continue the communication with.
Once done, the card will answer the response and this is.
And.
This response confirms the reception of PS request to continue with the bit rate selected by the PS
command.
So all this part is the layer three part of the communication.
Until here the communication is always done at 106 kilobit per second.
Then we will start the exchange of information.
The exchange of information is done through the block commands.
Here we will change some exchange some blocks from the reader to the card.
In fact, there are three types of blocks.
First one is the I blocks.
Second one S blocks and third one R blocks.
All these blocks are composed by, first of all, a PCB, which is a one byte.
Then the Sid which is also one byte.
Then the NAD which is also one byte.
Then we have the INF which is the information field, which is the information that the I block will
send.
For example, if it's, for example, if the reader wants to select a passport, he will select he will
send an I block for passport.
If we will select an ID card, he will select.
He will send an I block for ID card, for transport, for banking card, etc., etc. and then we have
the EDC which consists of two bytes.
So then these three type of blocks are presented by this part.
So we use the I block to convey and to convey the information.
For example, we want to ask the car the passport for some data.
For example for the the MRC for the information about the person, about any information that we can
extract from the past, the past.
So we send an I block asking for these certain, these certain or these information that the passport
contains.
So the I block, we use it to exchange information between the reader and the cart.
Then the second type of blocks is the S block.
Here we have three types of S block.
The first one is the WTA waiting time extension.
For example, sometimes the reader send an A block to the card and the card cannot answer immediately,
so he the card will need some time to prepare the answer.
So at that time the reader will send the first I block.
Then the card will send a WTA saying that I will need more time to prepare my answer.
Then the reader will say okay, by sending another WTA, X and so on and so on and so on.
This exchange of WTA can be two WTA.
It can be four, ten, 20.
Depends of the type of information that they will exchange.
It depends also on the speed.
When when the communication is quicker the number of WTA will be shorter and so on.
Then we have the deselect the deselect we we we set the reader send the deselect when there is a problem
with the communication, so the reader will deselect the card.
And the third type is the S parameters.
And we use the S parameters.
The reader send an s parameter in order to ask and to check if the card supports the very high baud
rate speeds.
The the the the the CBR.
The VBR consists of 1.7mbps, 3.4mbps, and 6.8mbps of speed.
So the reader will send an S parameter and the card will will answer with an S parameter, saying if
it supports the very high baud rate or not, and what until which value it can support.
And finally we have the R block.
The purpose of the R block is to convey a positive or negative acknowledgments.